# GIOVANNI PEREZ

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

# Summary

I am a software developer with a knack for fostering relationships between people and data. Two years ago I moved to Austin, and now that I am back in Chicago I am looking to contribute to the performance of one of the best cities in the world. Because of my background in informatics, I can focus on immediate needs while keeping track of the big picture.

## Skills

Primary: Javascript, HTML, CSS, MongoDB, Node.js, Ruby, Github, Python, Docker, Hyperledger, Gulp, Sinatra, React.js, Angular, Salesforce, Express.js, Chai, Mocha, Rails Exposed To: Tableau, Python, SQL, JIRA, Postman/JSON, Agile, Microstrategy, Splunk

### Contact

- giovanni\_perez4@yahoo.com
- perezg.io
- **\** 708-228-2519
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/gperez13/
- https://github.com/gperez13

# **Projects**

RxChain Dec 2017 - Current

RxChain is a Blockchain based Pharmaceutical application aimed at bridging the gap between hospital EMR systems and Pharmacy records while reducing drug abuse & operation inefficiencies. It uses IBM's Hyperledger technology to eliminate PHI breaches and is displayed through a React front end interphase. I am currently working on deploying the Hyperledger model using Docker. Soon, the app will also contain CRUD elements and have the React interphase updated to accommodate the API calls and improve cosmetic features. Lastly, I am also working on a mapping tool to find the location of your nearest pharmacy.

#### Rate Your Politician

Oct 2017 - Oct 2017

Rate My Chicago Alderman is a politician rating project aimed at engaging Chicago citizens in local politics. The full stack site has been created using HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, D3.js, JSON, MongoDB, mLabm, Sessions, and Express. It has been deployed with Heroku, but I am thinking about redeploying it on a larger server in case it picks up traffic. Prior to redeployment, I will fix some routing issues that render the wards incorrectly and work with the Sessions so that users can only alter records they create.

#### BulbasaurGuac

Sep 2017 - Sep 2017

This is a video game resembling one of many space shooter games from the 80's. Using Phaser libraries, I was able to add a physics element to manipulate objects in a canvas. The project allowed me to familiarize myself with Tiled, jQuery, and DOM manipulation. In the future I would like to clean up the code thoroughly as well as add animation onto the sprites. A bug also occurs when winning and losing simultaneously. The game can also benefit from additional features such as power ups or making enemies less predictable.

# **Employment**

# The Advisory Board Company

Austin, Texas

Member Support Analyst

Apr 2016 - Jul 2017

- Contributed 19.73% of positive survey feedback in a 14-member world class service support team
- Provided 3350+ member solutions through Salesforce/JIRA tickets bridging cross-functional team performance and end users
- Generated internal demographic reports with Excel to facilitate internal and external healthcare operations

### Title Helpers Inc.

Chicago, IL

Contract Closer

Dec 2011 - Apr 2016

- Summarized legal residential documents to 2166+ borrowers in English or Spanish placing me as a top producer in the firm
- Established an average of 35 minutes per closing and a record of 6 minutes, often leading to repeat business and scheduling requests

# Education

DePaul University BusinessManagement- Entrepreneurship 2014

General Assembly

Web Development Immersive 2017